### **Professional Summary**

Having 7+ years of IT experience, with technical expertise in HP QC, ALM, QTP, SAP FICO and Software Testing.

Leading a team of 2 testing resources and responsible for testing related deliveries. As part of my assignments I have been into Requirement Analysis, Preparing Testing Documents, Quality Assurance, Defect Analysis and Application Maintenance.

Involved in Functional testing, System Testing, Integration Testing, Regression Testing and also overall Application testing with good exposure to SDLC, STLC and Bug Lifecycle

I have also developed Test Scenarios, Test Plans, Test Cases and Test Reports and customized scripts and created Automation Framework's according to client's requirements.

Good understanding in Automation testing using various frameworks like Hybrid ,Modular and Business Process Testing frameworks in HP QTP with HP Quality center / Application Lifecycle Management tools.

I also possess excellent SAP Domain knowledge in Finance and Controlling Area

Involved in testing various applications like Web based, Windows SAP and Stand Alone applications

Involved in the Defect Tracking Management for various applications, through JIRA

Very comfortable to work both in a team environment and also individually.

Good analytical thinker & able to work individually & handle teams effectively & efficiently and also able to grab new technologies & things ASAP.

#### **Awards and Achievements**

Proficiency in leading and mentoring individuals to maximize productivity

A good listener with the ability to communicate effectively and to work in tandem with others

## **Experience Details**

Organization	Designation	Duration
Mahindra Satyam	Test Lead / Senior Quality Analyst	Feb/2013 - Till Date
Hewlett Packard	QA Lead	May/2011 - Sep/2012
Sansa Technology	Quality Assurance Instructor	Jan/2010 - Nov/2010
Misys Software Solutions	QA Tester (Manual & Automation)	Feb/2008 - Oct/2009
HCL Technologies	QA Tester & Customer Support Engineer	Oct/2006 - Jan/2008

#### Skills

Primary skill category	Software Testing
Secondary skills	Testing Functional &Testing Automation
Project acquired skills	QTP VB Scripting QC
Primary domain	IT
Trained skills	HP Quality Center , HP ALM & QTP
Linguistic skills	English , Tamil , Telugu
QTP frameworks	BPT,Hybird Framework, Keyword & Data Driven Framework

### **Work Experience**

### Project Profile#1: KMD Portal Automation - MSAT

QA Expert	Feb/2013 Till Date

Project Type	Automation – SAP Portal & R3	
Client	KMD Denmark	
Organization	Mahindra Satyam	
Location	Offshore: Bangalore	Onsite: Aalborg, Denmark
Duration	Offshore: Feb 2013 - till date	Onsite: Mar 14 - May 14
Team Size	Project : 10	Module: 4
Environment	Languages:	VB Scripting
	Domain :	SAP FI,CO,SD
	Database :	ALM & QTP in build Test data
	Tools:	ALM , QTP
	O/S:	Windows XP & Win7
Functional	QA - Manual & Automation Testing	

# **Project Description:**

KMD is one of Denmark's largest IT and software companies, with branches in Copenhagen, Århus, Odense and Aalborg. The majority of KMD's business derives from software development, and the company develops and delivers IT solutions for the local government, central government and private markets. We use our insight into our customers, processes and employees to deliver IT that optimizes and develops our customers' businesses. We have offices throughout Denmark, which means that we are close at hand and flexible. TechM provides KMD with much needed extra hands in SAP programming

# Contribution:

- Development of the Test scripts through QTP and executed the same with the help of ALM
  using Business Process Testing Framework, for Portal Mobility and User Interface team.
- Preparation of Test Cases in ALM & Setting up ALM for Test Cycle Designing the test
  cases using Functional specifications. Also, used ALM for Defect Tracking Validated the
  Defects using V&V process.

# Project Profile#2: Product Lifecycle Management Project (PLCM)

QA Lead	May/2011 - October/2012

Project Type	PLCM	
Client	QA LeadHewlett Packard	
Organization	Artech Info systems & Blue Star InfoTech	
Location	Offshore: Bangalore	Onsite: Nil
Duration	Offshore: May/2011October/2012	Onsite: Nil
Team Size	Project: 8	Module: 5
Environment	Languages:	VB Scripting
	Database :	SQL
	Tools:	Quality Center, QTP, JIRA
	O/ S:	Windows
Functional	QA - Manual & Automation Testing	

### **Project Description:**

The Process Lifecycle Management (PLCM) provides overall guidance and direction for those who are developing process content. It's primarily focused on processes that are expected to become part of the Hewlett-Packard Global Method (HPGM) environment. The PLCM is referred to as a process. Those that are following the PLCM process are either trying to create a process or significantly improve a process.

#### Contribution:

- Hosting & organizing daily Status meetings for Test Life Cycle. Managing the QA activities for the PLC Team
- Preparation of Test Plans for Project Management and Metrics for Test Case Management
- Preparation of Test Cases in QC & Setting up QC for Test Cycle Designing the test cases using Functional specifications.
- Used JIRA for Defect Tracking and Validating the Defects raised using JIRA for V&V process.
- Performing QC Administrative tasks like adding a user to a project through the QC Admin interface, answering basic questions on how to use the product.
- Analysis of the Product Performance & Automation Preparation of Automation scripts thru
  the Hybrid Framework in QTP for various Projects
- Reporting & managing various Projects & collecting more information for the same. QC Dash Board Setup for various Projects

# Project Profile#3: Quality Assurance Training (QA & QC Processes)

Software QA Instructor January/2010 - November/2010
---

Project Type	Software Quality Assurance Training	
Client	QA Trainer—Sansa Technology	
Organization	Sansa Technology	
Location	Offshore: Nil	Onsite: California, USA
Duration	Offshore: Nil	Onsite: Jan 2010-Nov2012
Team Size	Project : 8 - 10	Module: 8-10
	Database :	SQL
	Tools:	HP QC, QTP, Test Director, ALM, Load Runner
	O/ S:	Windows
Functional	QA - Manual & Automation Testing	

# **Project Description:**

Provided Training Programs for Corporate and Individuals. The trainings were excellent source for quickly adapting the changing professional world and preparing people to meet and excel the new challenges.

The trainings help to fill the gap that exists between formal education, IT experience and the skills they need to effectively perform the job as an IT professional.

#### Contribution:

- Software Quality Assurance Training Manual & Automation techniques Black box Testing & Automation Tools
- Used HP QTP & QC for Automation & Manual testing
- Used Load Runner & Test Loads for performance testing

Quality Engineer	February/2008 - October/2009
Quality Engineer	rebiualy/2006 - Octobel/2009

Project Type	Hospital Management Systems	
Client	Quality EngineerMisys Software Solutions	
Organization	Misys Software Solutions	
Location	Offshore: Bangalore Onsite: Nil	
Duration	Offshore: February/2008October/2009	Onsite: Nil
Team Size	Project: 30	Module: 5
	Database :	SQL
	Tools:	Test Director, Quality Center, N Cover Tool
	O/S:	Windows
	Hardware:	Medical Devices
Function	Manual And Automation Testing	

# **Project Description:**

Allscripts Enterprise (formerly Touch Works EHR) is the clinical software solution of choice for multispecialty and specialty practices as well as academic medical centers and hospital sponsored initiatives. Uniquely designed for the specific needs of physicians in today's increasingly interconnected health care environment, Allscripts Enterprise fully empowers and connects organization clinically, operationally, and financially

### Contribution:

- Responsible for Analyzing and testing programs and quality documents related to software Testing
- Preparation and Execution of Test Scripts for Unit/Code/Functional level Testing
- Preparation of Test Cases in QC & Setting up QC for Test Cycle Designing the test cases using Functional specifications.
- Worked in interfaces with the knowledge in HIPPA and HL7 messages
- Worked on Defect leakage Metrics within the Product by Analyzing the root cause of the issue
- QC Administrative Tasks Adding / Deleting Users. Customizing Projects & related activities

# Project Profile#5: Quality Assurance & Product Servicing-QA & QC Processes

Project Type	BT Products and Services	
Client	Quality Engineer & Customer Support Engineer HCL Technologies	
Organization	HCL Technologies	
Location	Offshore: Chennai	Onsite: Nil
Duration	<b>Offshore</b> : Oct 2006 Jan 2008	Onsite: Nil
Team Size	Project: 15	<b>Module</b> : 8-10
	Database :	SQL
	Tools:	HP QC, QTP
	O/s:	Windows
Functional	QA - Manual & Automation Testing	

### **Project Description:**

BT Broadband Services is the major Telecom Services in UK.I was working in the Customer Support Team as a QA person and later promoted as Customer Support Executive. Worked with Manual test scripts & cases with the help of Quality Centre. Was also the part of Automation testing using HP QTP (Test scripts & integration of QC & QTP). Solved various issues of the customers and got appreciation from the clients and from my organization as well. Got spot awards and cash awards for the same.

#### Contribution:

- Analyzed open source inventories and documented system requirements & Preparation of System Requirements Document
- Analyzed the Database for BT Broadband Services and Products proposed a feasible DB model for storage
- Preparation of Test Cases in QC & Setting up QC for Test Cycle
- Preparation and Execution of Test cases for Unit/Code/Functional level Testing
- Preparation and Execution of major functionalities of the Services offered by BT Telecom and focused on the Customer Satisfaction reports
- Analyzed the various issues and the problems faced by the customers and their BT Products and networks

#### Education

Degree	Specialization	University	Year of passing
Post graduation	MBA HUMAN RESOURCE	Anna university	2009
Graduation	B.TECH INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY	Anna University	2006

# **Passport Details**

Passport Number	G3717065	
Valid Up To	26 Jun 2017	